Guide to the The Washington Metropolitan Area Ephemeral Publications Collection, 2006-2007 MS2216
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
The Washington Metropolitan Area Ephemeral Publications Collection
2006-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2216
0.25 Linear Feet
This is an artificial collection created by Special Collections and is composed of publications produced by Washington area organizations.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
This collection was created by Special Collections staff to house short runs or one-off issues of Washington D.C. focused publications.
Historical or Biographical Note
This is an artificial collection created by Special Collections and is composed of publications produced by Washington area organizations.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains market reports, program guides and magazines. This material dates from 2006 to 2007. Organizations include DC Preservation League, Staubach Corporate Services, Market Report, Washington JCC, The Writer Center and Greater Washington DC.
Collection Organization
Organized into six series; DC Preservation League publications, The Writer's Center publications, Staubach Corporation publications, Washington D.C. Jewish Community Center publications, Great Places publications, and Washingtoniana focused publications.
Economic conditions; Washington (D.C.); Programs; Jewish community centers; Exhibition buildings; Preservation and restoration; Architecture -- Washington (D.C.); Writer's Center (Bethesda, Md.); Jewish Community Center of Greater Washington; Staubach Company; D.C. Preservation League
- DC Preservation League publications, 2007; MS2216 Series 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains the 35th Anniversary Celebration program. The program contains a brief history of the organization from its creation in the early 1970's to Fall of 2006. This focus of this organization is the preservation of Washington DC historic buildings. Included is this organizations list of Most Endangered Places for 2006 as well as Landmark Nominations.
  - DC Preservation League 35th Anniversary Celebration Program, 01/25/2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Writer's Center publications, 2007; MS 2216 Series 2
  This series contains the Winter 2007 Writer's Center guide to programs, workshops and events pertaining to independent writing. Included is a brief history of the organization's creation in 1976. The focus of this organization is to build a community for independent writers in the Washington, DC metropolitan area.
  - The Writer's Center Guide to Programs and Events Winter 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Staubach Corporation publications, 2006; MS 2216 Series 3
  This series contains an economic market report for the 3rd quarter of 2006. The purpose of this report is to document regional economic conditions, vacancy rates, net absorption, rental rates and construction activity in relation to the regional real estate market. Also listed is a market overview and market outlook.
  - Staubach Corporate Services Market Report 3rd Quarter 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Washington D.C. Jewish Community Center publications, 2006; MS 2216 Series 4
  This series contains the November 2006 program. This program includes a brief history of the Washington, D.C. Jewish Community Center from its creation in 1926 to its condition in 2006 as well as listings of all events for November, 2006. Special attention is also given to the 17th Washington Jewish Film Festival with brief descriptions of all films and screenings. The organization's focus is to preserve and strengthen Jewish identity, heritage, tradition and values through social, cultural, recreational, and educational programs and services.
  - Center in the City the Magazine of the Washington DCJCC, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Great Places publications, 2006-2007; MS 2216 Series 5
  This series contains the 2006-2007 Great Places directory for Greater Washington, DC. This directory contains listings of various venues within the Greater Washington, DC area interested in hosting corporate or private events. Each venue listed has corresponding photographs, a brief description and contact information. Venues are arranged within the categories Museums and Theatres, Restaurants, Clubs and Lounges, Themed Events Spaces, Historical Properties, Mansions and Inns, Yachts, Conference Centers and Universities and Special outdoor venues. Also included is information and advice pertaining to event planning.
  - Great Places, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Washingtoniana publications, Series 6
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains publications about Washington D.C. or by D.C. agencies or entities.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - dcenter Architectural Dissent & Discourse, Undated; Series 6 (Box 1)
    This publication from The Catholic University of America's School of Architecture and Planning contains numerous articles about Washington D.C. including articles about the Georgetown and Anacostia waterfronts, The Vietnam War memorial, Henry Jame's Washington, the architecture of the Arena Stage, DC Water and Sewer Authority.